twinstarcu.com 2011-01-05

# Privacy Policy | TwinStar Credit Union

This document is also available for download in PDF format.

We encourage you to read the whole policy to understand how we use your information online and offline. 

### Our Privacy Pledge

At the Credit Union, we respect the privacy of our members. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. This notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by the Credit Union. This notice explains what types of member information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it.

###  Member Information We Collect

The Credit Union collects only relevant information about members that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires. We may collect personal and financial information about you (member information) that is “nonpublic”. The member information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:

_Application Information_ – We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide for membership, deposit account, EFT services, loans, insurance, or other Credit Union services. This information may include: name, address, e-mail address, Social Security number, birth date, phone number, employment and financial status, and credit history.

_Your Transactions_ – Any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, insurance transactions through Internet Home Banking, over the phone or at a branch, we retain the transaction information, including: your account number, the date, amount, location of the transaction, and other pertinent information.

_Credit Reports_ – When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you and we may use it to evaluate future account service requests.

### Member Information We Share

In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our affiliates and third party service providers. However, we only share information to the extent necessary to service your account or offer new services to you. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices, and greater convenience. Information we may have about former members is generally only shared or disclosed, if necessary, to enforce or administer an account or as required by law.

_Sharing Information with Credit Union Affiliates_ \- Our affiliates CUSTOM, Inc is a data processing company, and Financial Services Management Group LLC, provides financial services. We may share personal information (such as name, address, SSN, and account number, etc.) and account information (such as type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history, etc.) with our affiliates, so they can serve you more efficiently. Our affiliates do not use information we share to market their products or services and they maintain the same privacy standards as the Credit Union.

_Sharing Information With Third Party Service Providers_ – In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers, including data processing companies, check, ATM and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, credit reporting agencies, insurance companies, financial planners and securities firms, and financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These service providers/strategic partners act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We may share the following categories of information to third party service providers depending on the specific services provided:

  * Personal information (i.e. name, address, SSN, and account number, etc.)
  * Account information (i.e. type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history, etc.)
  * Transaction information (i.e. date, amounts, locations, and type of transactions, etc.)

We do not sell member information nor share your account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services. While we may assist in offering financial products and services of our affiliates or other financial service providers, we control the member information used to make such offers.

_Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted_ – We may share any member information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate.

### Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards

We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that member information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees and agents are permitted access to member information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees and agents have access to such member information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees and agents are trained to respect member privacy. No one except our employees and agents has regular access to the Credit Union computer system and records storage. The Credit Union has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your member information as we employ new technology in the future.

###  Online Privacy Protection

At www.twinstarcu.com we may obtain information online when you visit the website. This may include retaining information you provide to us on any online application, our Internet Home Banking or e-mail. To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. The application information we accept online and our Internet Home Banking service relies on industry standard “Secure Sockets Layer” (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communication. Any information you provide using an online application, or any information you send to us by e-mail will be treated with confidentiality.

_Protecting Children’s Information Privacy:_ Our online financial services are not designed for or directed toward children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children’s identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents.

### Privacy Policy Changes

We reserve the right to change this policy, and we will give you any notice required by law if we change this policy.

### Privacy Policy Inquiries

The Credit Union is owned by its members and governed by a Board of Directors that you elect. You can be confident that your financial privacy is a top priority of your Credit Union. We are required by law to provide you with this privacy notice to explain how we collect, use, and safeguard your personal financial information. If you have any questions about our privacy practices, contact us by calling 360-357-9917, ext. 4440 or 1-800-258-3115, ext. 4440, sending us an e-mail at privacy@twinstarcu.com, or writing to us at TwinStar Credit Union, P.O. Box 718, Olympia, WA 98507-0718.

_Updated October 1, 2008_
